FRANCIS OBETTA

FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

francischassobetta@gmaill.com | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn | @chasscepts

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack engineer always on the lookout for innovations. I have worked for over 8years as a Broadcast Engineer, during which time, in addition to my regular engineering duties, I developed many in-house software applications for the company. I spent the past 5months working on several real-life projects with a team made up of people from diverse backgrounds and in an environment that simulates a real-life work environment.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PHP. Mobile Development: Java, React Native. Desktop Development: C#, Electron.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Developer

February 2021 - Present

Flights — Developed a command-line utility to filter flight information from popular flight booking sites thus removing the inconvenience of browsing through many web pages to gather the same information.

Built with: Ruby.

Head Desk, Broadcast Engineering Department, Megalectrics Limited

March 2013 - Present

Audio Profiler – Developed and integrated an audio profiler into the existing Audio Output Line, improving the system while saving money on external service charges.

• Built with: C#.

Employee Management Portal - Developed a portal for the HR Department that integrates Leave Management, Appraisal, and Training removing the inconvenience of the paper system that was in use.

• Built with: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, MYSQL, PHP, Code Igniter.

MICROVERSE Remote February 2021 - Present

Mentor (Volunteer)

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

February 2021 - Present

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY OF NIGERIA NSUKKA

Bachelor Of Engineering

March 2000 - March 2005

Designed an interface to a Modem Chip using Assembly Language and C Programming Language. A typical use case is a branch sales office to synchronize data with the main office.